(upbeat music)
- Hello everyone, welcome
back to another lesson
with us here at EnglishPod,
my name is Marco.
- My name is Catherine and that's us.
- And that's us.
And today we're gonna talk
about a very common situation
when you're a couple,
when you have girlfriend.
- Honey, come on, it's cool.
- I wanna go, are you deep?
- You're taking forever.
- All right, who takes long, do you take
a long time to get ready to get dressed?
- Okay, I take longer to get ready,
but my boyfriend takes longer in general
because he's like checking
his email, playing video games.
Like, just, you know,
we call it lolly gagging.
He's just like being kind of slow.
- I'm the opposite, I usually
start getting ready later.
Like, if we have to
leave at nine, I'll start
getting ready at 8.30,
but I'll be ready by nine.
Because I take a shower
real fast, get dressed,
and I know what I'm gonna
wear and all my clothes are ready.
But on the other hand, my
girlfriend takes forever to get ready.
And she's like, oh, and
then, you know, the hair.
- Girls have makeup, and tights, and shoes.
- But this is what I understand.
If we're supposed to leave at nine,
why don't you start getting ready before?
- Never underestimate,
I mean, I don't know.
- For a craft donation.
- Hey, it's not even about procrastination.
Sometimes it just takes longer
to look good than other times.
- Right, well, in this
case, we're gonna be
looking at a lesson
where it's the opposite.
- The husband is taking
a long time to get ready,
and well, I don't think he has a
very good fashion sense, right?
- He does not.
And we're gonna learn
what that phrase means
in a minute here, but before we get going,
we've got a couple of words to preview
to help you understand what's
going on in today's dialogue.
- Very cabaret-y preview.
- All right, so vocabulary
preview today, we have two words.
The first one can be a
noun or a verb to iron.
- Or iron.
- Huh.
- So to iron basically means to
get the wrinkles out of clothes.
And so we use this,
iron is actually a metal.
It's a very important metal.
And an iron is a machine that we plug in.
We use it to get the
wrinkles, the lines out
of our shirts and our
skirts and everything.
And so it's actually a very important thing
to make sure that you
look nice and put together.
- Right, so you use an
iron to iron your shirt
or to your iron your skirt.
And then we have sandals.
My favorite type of shoe.
- Mine, too.
- Sandals.
- I have a friend who used to
say she had claustrophobic feet.
Her feet didn't like to be enclosed
spaces, so she only wore sandals.
- So these are open shoes,
open toe shoes, basically.
You wear them at the beach.
- Or you wear them in
the summer in general.
I'm wearing sandals right now.
- And you have different types of sandals,
like sandals and flip flops, right?
- Flip flops, I think they're called that
because they sound
like flip flop flop flop flop.
- When you walk.
- All right, so those are
our two words today.
Let's listen to the
dialogue for the first time.
And then we'll be back.
(upbeat music)
- Honey, come on, we're going to be late.
Honestly, you take longer
getting ready than I do.
- I was drying my hair
and ironing my shirt.
Can you come here for a sec?
I need your help.
- What is it?
Why are all these clothes on the bed?
- I don't know what to wear.
- Okay, give me your opinion.
Do you like the way this looks?
The striped short sleeve shirt with this
checkered sweater in my lucky sandals.
I like the cut and hem
line of these shorts.
So I think I'll wear these as well.
- Are you joking?
What am I going to do with you?
You're going to dinner
party, not to the beach.
Wear this shirt with a certain tire
bought you and there's corduro pants.
It's cheating outside so
you can wear this coat.
- Thanks, honey.
You have such a great fashion sense.
Now, what am I going to do with my hair?
(upbeat music)
- All right, we're back.
So interesting, this husband.
It sounded a lot like a
famous president, I think.
- He did, but we'll
get to that in a minute.
But before we do talk
about who this guy is,
I think it'd be a great idea to talk
about some of these clothing terms
because they're very
useful for when you wanna
go shopping and for
when you're getting dressed.
- Language takeaway.
- Okay, so the first word that we
have on language, takeaway is striped.
All right, you might have heard the
American flag called stars and stripes.
Stripes are those lines on clothing or on
flags that go up or down or left and right.
- Exactly, so if you have a striped
shirt, you have many lines on your shirt
that are going up and
down or left and right.
- Right, and I say with fashion, lines
that go left to right make you look fatter
and lines that go up and
down make you look thinner.
- And taller, and taller.
- Very good.
And now moving on, if
it's summer and you wanna
wear a shirt, you can wear
a short sleeve the shirt.
- All right, this is important.
So most people like to
wear short sleeve shirts
in the summertime
because they're cooler.
And in the wintertime, that means
we like to wear long sleeved shirts.
- Okay, so the sleeves are
basically the arms of the shirt.
- Exactly.
- So you say short sleeved, very good.
And then we have a checkered shirt
or a checkered sweater in this case.
Okay, so checkered means
there are little squares
on the shirt and
usually one square is one
color and the next
square is another color.
So it looks like a checkered board.
- Very good.
- Like game, you know,
checkered or like a chess board.
- Exactly.
And so in this case, we've
got a guy who's trying
to wear a striped shirt
and a checkered sweater.
- That does not go out on the side now.
- No, too much stuff happening.
- It's too busy, too busy.
- All right.
- And not only that,
but he wanted to wear
shorts because he liked
the cuts and the hemline.
- Okay, these are actually terms that
we normally use with women's clothing
because you could say, I
like the cut of this dress.
I like the shape that it has.
- Very good.
- And hemline is the bottom of your
skirt or your trousers or your shorts.
And hemline, we could
say, my mother used to
sit as to me, the
hemline is much too high.
- That's too short, that
skirt is not appropriate.
- Yeah, so it's nice to
have a hemline at the knee.
(laughing)
- All right, so the cut is the shape
that the piece of clothing
has like pants or skirts.
And the hemline would be
the place where it ends, right?
The skirt, for example.
- Like it pretty much tells
you the length of something.
- Very good.
And now, well, and now the wife steps in.
She's like, no, no,
you're not wearing this.
She's telling them that
she has to wear nice
clothes and among
those items is a silk tie.
Okay, so classic Father's Day gift.
- Silk tie.
- I've given this one a couple of times.
The silk tie is a neck tie, a
long neck tie, that's made of silk.
- Silk is a very soft material, right?
Very expensive as well.
- It can be, especially Italian silk.
And I've always actually
wanted to have silk sheets.
- Ooh, see, I don't know.
I feel like they would get
very warm in the summer.
- Well, in the winter, it would be awesome,
but probably very cold
in the winter as well.
- Yeah, I don't know.
- Well, it's one of those things.
And then she's also telling them
to wear some corduroy pants.
- Okay, so it sounds like this
might be a winter dialogue
because corduroy is not
something you wear in
the summer because
it's very heavy and thick.
Corduroy actually is a fabric that
usually has these kind of ribs or ridges.
And so there's little lines in the fabric
that make it quite thick and
rough when you're almost not rough,
but they make it feel very
unique when you touch it.
- Yeah, it's not smooth.
It's a little bit rough, the fabric.
Very good.
So those are all the clothing
items that we've looked at today.
There's a lot of them
and obviously we'll post
a couple of pictures on the
side so you can see better
what a silk tie looks like,
or especially corduroy pants.
- Corduro, yeah.
- All right, so let's
listen to this dialogue.
Again, we're gonna
slow it down a little bit
and then we'll come back
and look at some of the phrases.
- Honey, come on, we're going to be late.
Honestly, you take longer
getting ready than I do.
- I was drying my hair
and ironing my shirt.
Can you come here for a sec?
I need your help.
- What is it?
Why are all these clothes on the bed?
- I don't know what to wear.
Okay, give me your opinion.
Do you like the way this looks?
- The striped short sleeve shirt with
this checkered sweater in my lucky sandals.
I like the cut and hemline of these
shorts, so I think I'll wear these as well.
- Are you joking?
What am I going to do with you?
We're going to dinner
party, not to the beach.
Wear this shirt with
the silk tie I bought you
and those corduroy pants is chilly
outside so you can wear this coat.
- Thanks, honey.
You have such great fashion sense.
Now, what am I gonna do with my hair?
All right, we're back, so now
let's start with Fluency Builder.
Fluency Builder.
- Okay, these are classic
couple phrases, right?
These are phrases you hear among couples
and the first one is maybe
more common to hear
from the female and but it's
not unknown on the male end.
So we have this question.
Do you like the way this looks?
- So while the person is saying this,
they would maybe be moving to
the side a little bit, but modeling it.
- Do you like the way this looks?
So basically you're saying,
do you like what I'm wearing?
Does it look good on you?
- Does it look good exactly?
You could also say, hey,
I like the way this looks.
When you're trying to
buy something at the
store and so do you
like the way this looks
is a way for you to ask
the other person's opinion
of how you look?
- And also another common phrase, especially
with men who have no fashion sense,
the wife says, what am
I going to do with you?
- Okay, this is an interesting phrase and
it needs some explanation I think because
the meaning is, well,
this is very difficult, right?
So you're being difficult or wow, you
need some help from me, I'm gonna help you.
- How am I going to help you
this much or all the time like this?
- Right, because she's pretty much saying
he has no idea about clothing and fashion.
So he's saying to her, what am she saying
to him, what am I going to do with you?
I mean, do you need so much help?
- Seriously, all right,
so, and the third phrase
that we saw, and we
said at the very beginning
is fashion sense.
- Okay, so this is actually
what the man needs help with.
- Fashion.
- He needs help with his fashion
sense because he has zero fashion sense.
And this is pretty much a way to say
how much someone knows
about fashion or appearances.
And so I can say, oh my friend Kathy,
she has amazing fashion
sense, so she always looks good.
- Right, so combining colors appropriately
or wearing the right types of shoes,
with the right types of
clothing, et cetera, fashions.
Or even just being able to
wear things that are good on her
or telling other people
what's good on them.
So fashion sense is the
ability to identify fashion
and look good and make
other people look good.
- All right, very good.
Let's listen to this dialogue
for the very last time
and we'll come back and
talk a little bit more about
fashion because it's a
very interesting topic here.
(upbeat music)
- Honey, come on, we're going to be late.
Honestly, you take longer
getting ready than I do.
- I was drawing my
hair and ironing my shirt.
Can you come here for a sec?
I need your help.
- What is it?
Why are all these clothes on the bed?
- I don't know what to wear.
Okay, give me your opinion.
Do you like the way this looks?
The striped short sleeve shirt
with this checkered sweater.
My lucky sandals, I like the
cut and hemline of these shorts.
So I think I'll wear these as well.
- Are you joking?
What am I going to do with you?
You're going to dinner
party, not to the beach.
Wear this shirt with this entire
boy, you, and there's cordray pants.
It's chilly outside, so
you can wear this coat.
- Thanks, honey, you have
such great fashion sense.
Now, what am I going to do with my hair?
(upbeat music)
- All right, we're back.
You lived in Italy for a while.
How is the fashion over there?
Is it extreme like we see on the runways
because I honestly don't understand fashion?
- Well, the thing about runways is
that that's not how normal people dress.
- Well, yeah, that's what I understand.
Why do they have these fashion shows
if people don't really buy
these types of clothing?
- Well, sometimes people like stores,
for example, big stores, department stores,
will buy fashions off of the runway, and
they'll kind of change them a little bit
so that they're more appropriate
for normal consumption.
That means for normal
people who want to wear them.
But the runway fashions are actually,
they're kind of like exaggerations of trends
that will happen in the shopping
world, in the commercial world.
So the things that you see are
like big blown up exaggerations
and we take bits and
pieces of those in our daily
lives to dress up so
different colors or fabrics
or like oftentimes you
see kind of military outfits
and so that will translate into military
jackets that are very popular one season.
And so Italy definitely
counts as a very
fashionable country
but it's not crazy people.
Every once in a while you see someone
with crazy clothes but I think Jeff.
- Japan is much more crazy as far as style.
- Yeah, Asian countries
such as Japan or South Korea,
they have very, also unique fashion as well
but it's very extreme to a certain point
and the color combinations
they do is like red sneakers
with green pants and like a blue jacket.
It's very crazy.
- Right.
- And very bright.
- And you often see these shoes,
you know, we call them platform shoes.
They're, it's kind of like you're
standing on a brick all around the view.
- And they're, you know,
they're seven inches tall
and you see these little
girls when these big shoes
and I just, I'm so scared when I see them
'cause I feel like they're gonna fall over.
- The other thing is that
fashion is so expensive
if you actually wanna buy
something that's in like an authentic,
I don't know, Carolina,
Reda or Oscar de la
Renta or something
like that, it's so expensive.
- It is, but you know,
high fashion is expensive.
- Yeah.
- Fashion is not, doesn't have to be.
You can, you can be
fashionable just looking at
different stores and going to secondhand
shops and making your own clothes.
I mean, it's all about a sense
of personal style and dressing
yourself to be unique or
you can get at the fake market.
- Or you can go to
the fake market, exactly.
- All right, that's all the
time we have for today, guys.
I hope you enjoyed this lesson.
Please come to a website and
comment at www.EnglishPod.
com and if you have
any other suggestions
or maybe your own pictures of crazy fashion,
you can post, we're glad to see them.
So we'll see you guys there.
- Yeah, as Marcos, I hope
to see you on the website.
That's about it for today.
So, goodbye everyone. - Bye.
(upbeat music)